# **James Smith**

Alta Floresta, Brazil (407) 545-7812 · accenicsinc@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/james-smith-ruo

Senior full-stack engineer with a bachelor's degree in computer science and 10+ years of experience in web & mobile app development. Expert-level knowledge owner who has participated in 20+ web products & 5+ mobile apps and actively leads architecture development.

#### **SKILLS**

# Frontend Development

- 5+ years of MERN, SPA Experience (React, Redux, Node, Express, MongoDB, Restful API, GraphQL)
- 3+ years of **SSG**, and **SSR** Experience (Gatsby, Next.js, Docusaurus)
- 2+ years of JAM Experience (Gatsby, Contentful, Prismic)
- 2+ years of Serverless Web App Experience (React, Firebase, AWS Amplify, Dynamodb)
- 2+ years of Shared Components Experience (Storybook, Material, Bootstrap, SaaS, Styled-components, Nx, Lerna)

# Mobile Development

• 5+ years of iOS/Android Social, Game, Service Mobile App Experience (React Native, Expo, Firebase, Testflight)

# **Backend Development**

- 4+ years of *MVC* Experience (Express, Django, Laravel)
- 4+ years of *RDBMS*, *NoSQL* Experience (MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB)

#### EXPERIENCE

2019/09 - 2021/09 SUPREMA GRUPO

Alta Floresta, Mato Grosso

#### Senior Frontend Tech Lead

- Managed 5+ frontend developers to build 4+ services (*user web app, customer/admin portal, learning web app*) and closely collaborated with business development, data analysis, operations, and marketing teams
- Mentored 3+ junior developers by onboarding, day-to-day PR review, and personal/team demo to ensure high-quality product delivery and improve collaborative team culture
- Increased development speed & productivity by 30%, by building solid application architecture using atomic design pattern, sophisticated module splitting, and perfect E2E testing module
- Reduced API call/Data consuming rate and potential bug rate by 60%, by building optimized data fetching/process/consuming pipeline (*GraphQL*, *Reselect*, *Redux*, *React memo hooks*, *React lifecycles*)
- Reduced MVP creation timeline by 50% by building portable company shared UI/UX/data pattern based on variable technologies (Storybook, Sass, Bootstrap, React, plugin), NX-based package management system, easy-to-learn & well-optimized code pattern, and detailed guide documentation

2015/09 - 2019/09 LACTVIT

Alta Floresta, Mato Grosso

#### Senior React/React Native Engineer

- Provided 65% no-coding-customizability of company portal & blog website by building no-coding architecture using component auto-generation system based on highly-optimized atom-level components, contentful document models, and sophisticated Contentful GraphQL/Gatsby-plugin/Data-pipeline/Components paradigm
- Reduced documentation site development/maintenance cost by 30% by creating SSG development/codebase pattern based on Next, and Docusaurus, and providing highly-extendable site architecture including multi-language features based on Crowdin, Smart doc version control system, etc.
- Built a state-of-the-art architecture of about 5+ hybrid mobile applications from scratch and led its development from API integration to user-interface development
- Provided highly-optimized product development streamlining by creating sophisticated module architecture, unit testing based on Storybook & Jest, and deployment system based on App Center & Code-Push

2014/09 - 2015/09 Run2biz

Brasilia, Goias

# Frontend Engineer

- Built 3+ big web applications (Education System, Surgery Management system) from scratch and played a vital role in the software architecture development
- Optimized original codebase by 40% by creating & refactoring reusable components and data processing pipeline

# **EDUCATION**

2009/09 - 2013/09 GOIAS FEDERAL UNIVERSITY

Brasilia, Goias